(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.2",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
A long, long time ago
in a land far, far away
lived Polka, a beautiful maiden who drew the ire of her queen
for she too wished to be the prettiest being in the world.
One day, Polka was walking through the forest when she met an old woman.
"Would you like an apple? My, but these are ripe and tasty," she said.
Tempted by the offer, Polka gladly took a bite.
As Polka was spellbound by how delicious the apple was, the old woman vanished.
It was then that Polka made the realization:
the Apple was poisoned.
But it was too late.
Polka collapsed to the ground helplessly.
Many moons later, the fateful moment had arrived.
A prince had appeared before Polka.
He was captivated by her beauty and eventually gave her the kiss of fate...
And Polka awakened, ever so beautiful!
Her beauty had not diminished over time,
as though reality was but a virtual concept to her...
Hm? But wait, Polka is a virtual idol, so poisoned apples won't work on her.
But don't get me wrong, Polka-senpai is incredibly pretty!
Now, Polka-senpai, go on and show off your reborn self as an idol!
白い雪のプリンセスは
作詞・作曲：のぼる↑
The Snow White Princess is
Lyrics & Music: Noboru↑
ありがとう！
Thank you!
鏡よ鏡よ鏡さん
Mirror, mirror, oh mirror
世界で一番可愛いのは
Who is the cutest in the world?
やめてよ 棘のような視線
Stop it, those thorn-like glares
丸く優しいふりした彼女
She who pretended to be round and kind
素敵な晩餐をもてなした
Served a wonderful dinner
笑み、薄れてゆく
My smile fades away
白の中で
Inside the whiteness
夢を見てる
I'm dreaming
いつかの御伽噺
Of a fairy tale from long ago
時が止まる
Time stops
お願いキスで目を目を覚まして欲しいの
Please, wake me up with a kiss
白い棺から連れ出すように
As if leading me out of a white coffin
突き刺さる憎しみはドラマチックな事情
The piercing hatred is a dramatic circumstance
祈っても君はまだ来ない
Even if I pray, you still don't come
鏡よ鏡よ鏡さん
Mirror, mirror, mirror on the wall
ネクタイ任せや本番合図
Leaving it to the tie, the signal for the show
ナースの小人はいるけども
I have nurse's dwarfs, but...
助ける素振り知らんぷり
They feign ignorance, not lifting a finger to help
笑み、ひとつぶの
A smile, and a single...
涙さえも
...tear, even that...
拭えなくて
...I cannot wipe away
呼吸もままならない
I can barely even breathe
視界、失せた
My vision has faded
嫌よ、だから早く逃がして欲しいの
No, so I want you to let me escape soon
訳は聞かないで答えられない
Don't ask why, I can't answer
止まらない憎まれはスカイラインの事情
The endless being-hated is a skyline circumstance
もうすぐでいなくなるのかな
I wonder if I'll be gone soon...
途切れてく
Breaking off...
命の音
...the sound of life
毒リンゴを
A poison apple...
食した少女のように
...like the girl who ate it
お願いキスで目を目を覚まして欲しいの
Please, wake me up with a kiss
胸の中の声届きますか
Can my inner voice reach you?
階段を上ったらドアを開けるだけで
If I climb the stairs, just by opening the door...
見つかるよ
...it will be found
お願いキスで目を目を覚まして欲しいの
Please, wake me up with a kiss
白い棺から連れ出すように
As if leading me out of a white coffin
突き刺さる憎しみはドラマチックな事情
The piercing hatred is a dramatic circumstance
祈っても君はまだ来ない
Even if I pray, you still don't come
ああ、消えてしまう
Ah, it's going to disappear
その前に
Before that happens
改めまして！
Hello again!
尾丸ポルカです！
I'm Omaru Polka!
あ、違った。えーと...
Oh, wait. Er...
ホロライブ5期生、尾丸ポルカです！
I'm Omaru Polka from Hololive's 5th Gen!
よろしくお願いします！
Nice to meet you!
なんでこんな改まってるかっていうと
The reason I'm being so formal is...
やっぱり、ほら、アイドル衣装なわけじゃないですか。
...well, as you can see, it's because of this idol outfit.
いつもはサーカスの座長を目指す
Usually I'm er, a circus performer...
サーカス団員としてやってるんだけど
...aiming to be the ringmaster, but...
こうやってね、改めて、ホロライブ皆様が通ってきた道、
...like this, following the path that everyone in Hololive has taken,
いやその服に袖を通すと、なると！
...or rather, putting on these clothes!
あ、全然違うわ、気分。ははは。
Oh, my mood is totally different. Haha.
今、気分がめちゃくちゃお淑やかな感じになっちゃったんだけど、
I feel very ladylike right now,
あー、え、可愛いかな？
Ah, er, do I look cute?
あのね、さっきねねでも見たと思うんだけど、
You know, like you probably saw with Nene earlier,
ねねとお揃いの形で、これねいっぱい種類がある、
...this is the same style as Nene's, and there are many types,
いっぱい？3個だっけ？あるんだけど、
Many? Was it three? Well, there are several,
ねねとお揃いの形になりました。
...but mine is the same style as Nene's.
あとの後続組がどうなるか知らない！
I don't know what the ones coming after me will wear!
はぁー、そんなわけで、いやぁー
*Sigh* Anyway, wow...
ちょっと緊張してしまいました。ポルカ。
...I got a bit nervous. Polka.
はぁ... なんか
Phew... like...
本当に... ま、来るんだ来るんだと思ってましたが
really... well, I kept thinking it would come, it would come,
この日がようやく、つい、ついに来るんだと。
but finally, at last, this day has come.
あとこれ2回ぐらい繰り返されますからね。
I'll probably repeat this about two more times.
ま、ついにこの日がやってきたんだと。
Well, finally this day has arrived.
はい。ありがとう。
Yes. Thank you.
今日はちょっとじゃちょっと... コーレスしていいかな？
Today, maybe... can I do a call-and-response?
え、だめだ。アイドルこんなポーズしないか。
Wait, no. Idols don't strike this kind of pose.
コーレスしていいかなー！！
Can I do a call-and-response!?
えー... お前らポルカは可愛いですかー！？
Um... Everyone, is Polka cute!?
うーーん、もっと！
Mmm, more!
もっと！せーの！
More! Ready, go!
おおー！いいぞ！もっと！いいぞ！いいぞ！
Ohhh! Nice! More! Nice! Nice!
来い！来い！来い！来い！あーーー、ありがとう！
Come on! Come on! Come on! Aaaah, thank you!
ふぅ... 今の、大丈夫だったかな？
Phew... was that okay just now?
ちゃんと... あのね、日々ね、あのちょっとツンデレな人が多いからさ
Properly... you know, there are many tsundere people every day,
ポルカのこと可愛いって言えない人も、今だったら言えるかも。今！
so those who can't say I'm cute might be able to say it now. Now!
今しかない！逆に今しかないよ！
It's now or never! In fact, now is the only time!
へへ... どう？可愛いかな？
Hehe... How is it? Am I cute?
よし、もう一回ちょっと、もうそれ以上やると照れるな。
Alright, one more... If I do it any more, I'll get embarrassed.
ガチの照れが入っちゃうんで... え、あの、やめ... どう...？
I'm actually starting to get embarrassed... wait, um, stop... how...?
え、どんどん下がっちゃった。
Wait, I'm gradually shrinking back.
ううううう...
Uuuuuuu...
はい。ね。
Yes. Right.
これね、ポルカの見てほしい点としては、大きいリボンですかね。
Regarding points I want you to see, it's the big ribbon, I guess.
あとお星様がね、髪の毛につきましたよと。
And stars have been attached to my hair.
どういうこっちゃね、これ。可愛いでしょ？
What's up with this? It's cute, right?
いや、この形すごい憧れてたんだ。
Man, I've really longed for this style.
なんかポルカっていつもさ、サーカス衣装がそもそもタンクトップだから
Like, Polka's circus outfit is a tank top to begin with,
ちょっと逆に清楚みたいな。
so this is kind of pure/wholesome in contrast.
こちらのほうが安心した。
I feel more relieved with this.
えー... いや、これで落ち着いた。なんかすごいねこれ。腕にこんなのも付いてるんだよ。
Yeah... I've settled down now. This is amazing. There's even this on my arms.
おおー！はー先輩とお揃いになれたし
Ohhh! I got to match with Haachama-senpai,
同期でこれでこれからライブもできるし。
and now I can do lives with my gen-mates in this.
あー... はい、というわけでね、ライブぜひね、えーと楽しみにしてください。
Ah... Yes, so please look forward to the lives.
あの3月の皆のライブも楽しみにしててください。
Please look forward to everyone's live in March as well.
というわけで何これなんか... あれしよう、あれ。
So, what is this... let's do that, that.
スクショタイム... じゃなくて、撮影会タイム。
Screenshot time... no, photoshoot time.
え、ちょっと、アイドルってどういうポーズするの？
Wait, what kind of poses do idols do?
え、アイドルってちょっと... なんかすごい...
Wait, idols are kind of... like, very...
ポルカ一年半ぐらいにして、初めてなんか違う意味の羞恥心を今知ってるんだけど。
After a year and a half, for the first time I'm feeling a different kind of embarrassment.
え？え？これしか出ない。
Huh? Huh? Only this pose comes out.
待って。えーとね... え、え、こうこういう？え何だろう？ピース？
Wait. Um... like this? Uh, what should it be? A peace sign?
普通にピースかな？
Just a normal peace sign?
分かんない、なんかもう照れてる照れてる...
I don't know, I'm just so embarrassed...
えーと... こんな感じ？もうこれっていつもポルカやってるよな。
Um... Like this? But I always do this.
イェーイ！え、あ、ちょっと近づいてさ。
Yay! Oh, let me get a bit closer.
今日は楽しんでるか？
Are you guys having fun today?
ういぃぃ！皆愛してるぞ！キラだぞ！
Wiii! I love you all! It's 'Kira'!
はぁ... こんなライブで言ったことないわ。恥ずかしい恥ずかしい...
Phew... I've never said that in a live before. So embarrassing...
恥ずかしいなんか... え、ごめん。今日一人で笑ってばっかだわ。
It's embarrassing... sorry. I've been laughing by myself all day today.
あ、全然もうアイドルって何か分かんないけど、えーと... えーと...
I have no idea what an idol is anymore, but um...
これからも立派にホロライブ五期生、尾丸ポルカとして頑張っていきます。
I will continue to do my best as Omaru Polka of Hololive's 5th generation.
やばい、このポーズじゃない、絶対違う。
Oh no, this isn't the right pose. Definitely not.
えーと... ニコ？
Um... Niko?
えーとニコ？分かんないな。つ...
Um, Niko? I don't know. Tsu...
ぱ！とびきり可愛い尾丸ポルカ。
Pa! Extremely cute Omaru Polka.
よしよしよし... はい、あのですね。
Alright, alright... Yes, so...
えーと... こんなにすごいどうしぶないのは、本当に初披露の時以来なんですが
It's really been since my debut that I've been this restless,
この後なんと、今日はリレーなんだな。
but today is actually a relay.
ラミィの配信、そしてその後が、最後ししろん... 最後じゃなかった！
Lamy's stream, and then finally Shishiron... wait, not finally!
ししろんと皆とライブするんで、よかったら見てください。
With Shishiron, we'll do a live with everyone, so please watch.
ハッシュタグは... えーと、えーと...
The hashtag is... um, um...
シャープ（#）ねぽらぼアイドル衣装で
#NepolaboIdolOutfit,
よろしくお願いします。
please support us.
まだまだ今日は始まったばかり、帰さないで。
Today has only just begun, don't let them go home.
というわけで... え、え、やばいなんか...
So... oh man, this is...
これは... これ... つ、え、分かんない。もう何をすればいいのか分かんない、こういう時。
This... I don't know anymore. I don't know what to do at times like this.
え、え、えーと、じゃあ最後の挨拶行きます。
Uh, well, let's do the final greeting.
せーの... バイバーイ！バイバーイ！
Ready... Bye bye! Bye bye!
これからもよろしく。本当に本当にこの服着させてくれてありがとう。
Please continue to support me. Thank you so much for letting me wear this.
尾丸ポルカでしたー！
This was Omaru Polka!
尾丸ポルカ アイドル衣装
Omaru Polka Idol Costume
じゃじゃーん！
Ta-da!
ということで、尾丸ポルカのアイドル衣装、お披露目だー！
And so, here's the reveal of Omaru Polka's idol costume!
見て見て！
Look, look!
アイドルだぞー！
I'm an idol!
みんな、似合ってるかなー？
Everyone, does it suit me?
この後もししろんの枠に続くから、みんな絶対見に来てね！
The relay continues on Shishiron's channel next, so make sure to watch!